准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
闹鬼海之霸
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
此处点餐
总共十块九毛五
That'll be 10.95
等一下
Wait a minute
就放在这边哪里来着的
Got it here somewhere
找到了
I got it
不给糖就捣蛋
Trick or treat
不是这么付的
That's not how this works
我下班了
My shift is over
新年快乐
Happy New Year
万圣节快乐
Happy Halloween
看得出来你们俩是要打扮成白痴
I see you're both dressing up as idiots
来过今年的万圣节
for Halloween this year
那可未必
Not quite
我们要打扮成
We're going as
一头海骡子
A sea-mule
咱俩好像扮的都是屁股这一半
I think we're both rear-ends
你自己承认的  别怪我
You said it, not me
没事
That's okay
反正也用不着上半身
we don't need a front half
我们要在我家过万圣夜
We're spending the night at my house
发糖果
Giving out candy
看恐怖片
And watching scary movies
音量开到最大
At full volume
还要尖叫
And screaming
一整晚
All night long
过万圣节光看电影可不行
You can't spend Halloween watching movies
必须得要有真正的恐慌
What you need is a real scare
所以  你们得去可怕的地方
So, you need to go somewhere scary
最好整晚都待在那里
And preferably stay there all night
要恐怖又空无一人的地方
Somewhere creepy and empty
就比如
Like, um
海之霸
海之霸吗
the Chum Bucket?
就那里  海之霸
Yeah, that's it, the Chum Bucket
从来就没人进去过
No one ever goes in there
多半是因为那里闹鬼了
Maybe because it's haunted
确实
Sure
海之霸里全是鬼
The Chum Bucket is full of ghosts
快把自己关进去  天亮之前别出来
Now lock yourselves in and don't come out 'til morning
谢了  章鱼哥
Thanks, Squidward
这一定会是史上最棒的万圣节
This is gonna be the best Halloween ever
对
Yeah
你要一起来吗
You wanna come with us?
我倒挺想
Wish I could
你们两个玩得开心点
You two have fun
海之霸
快  趁着没关门躲进去
Hurry, let's hide inside before they close
还真的闹鬼了
It is haunted
我看也没那么可怕嘛
I guess it isn't that scary
出口
厨房
那什么东西
What is that?
有人  也可能是有东西过来了
Someone or something is coming
快  躲进厕所里
Hurry, let's hide in the bathroom
我受不了万圣节
I can't stand Halloween
来启动防欢乐安保系统
Let's activate the anti-fun security system
免得那些来要糖果的过来敲门
before any of those trick or treaters come a-knocking
最高级别封锁
Maximum lockdown
完成
Check
战术监视烟雾
Tactical surveillance fog
完成
Check
好  现在关灯
Alright, now hit the lights
行了
There
这下不会有谁把这里误认成
No one would ever mistake this
过万圣节的地方了
for a place to celebrate Halloween
当然不会有了
Of course not
你都忘了挂骷髅跟南瓜灯
You forgot the skeletons and jack-o'-lanterns
好好好  凯伦
Yeah, yeah, yeah, Karen
我要上床睡觉了
I'm going to bed
我一直有打算要修的
I've been meaning to fix that
万圣节快乐  亲爱的老公
Happy Halloween, honey hubby
晚安
Good night
派大星  这里是不是阴森上了不少
Patrick, did it just get a lot spookier in here?
我要回厕所
I wanna go back to the bathroom
可能需要开一下灯
Maybe we just need some light
我都分不清自己是更紧张了
I can't decide if I'm m-more nervous
还是更兴奋了
or excited
我也一样
Neither can I
我知道可以问谁
I know who we can ask
章鱼哥
Squidward
派大星
Patrick
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
海之霸
The Chum Bucket?
我怎么会
How did I--
你们啥时候
When did you--
章鱼哥  我们现在这样子
Squidward, do we seem
是更紧张还是更兴奋
more nervous or excited?
你们样子像白痴
You seem like morons
那就放心了
Well, that's a relief
我要闪了
Now I'm leaving
别跟着我
And do not follow me
出口
门好像锁上了
I think the doors are locked
谢尔顿  入侵者警报
Sheldon, intruder alert
那群来过万圣节的混蛋
Those Halloween hooligans
让我看看
Lemme see 'em
我好兴奋能来废弃的海之霸过万圣夜
I'm so excited to be spending Halloween night
in the old abandoned Chum Bucket
跟好朋友派大星跟章鱼哥找魑魅魍魉
looking for ghosts and ghouls
with my best friends Patrick and Squidward
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
果然如此
Of course
那个白痴还真会带朋友来这过万圣节
That soft-headed sap
would bring his friends here for Halloween
既然他们想要恐惧
Well, if it's a scare they want
那我就吓死他们
Then I'll scare them to death
我的小鬼头
My little ghoul
总算有点万圣节的精神了
is finally getting into the Halloween spirit
厨房
好好好  这扇门也锁上了
Wonderful, this one's locked too
听说用过这个纸巾盒的人
I heard this napkin dispenser was used by a guy
消失了
who disappeared
听说这盐瓶还有胡椒瓶
I heard these salt and pepper shakers
里面其实
are actually
装的是其他调料
some other seasoning
听说从前有这两个傻子
I heard one time these two imbeciles
害得我整晚被反锁在海之霸里
locked me in the Chum Bucket all night
出去
Get out
笨
Stupid
混蛋
punks
海之霸还真的闹鬼了
The Chum Bucket really is haunted
我一定要逃出去
I gotta get out of here
那边那扇门好像开着的样子
There, that door looks open
抱歉
Sorry
我
I'm
没事
okay
他们跑我地下实验室去了
They went down into my basement lab
这下我可真能吓吓他们了
Now I can really scare them
这是什么地方
Where are we?
不知道
I don't know
摸黑找找电灯开关
Feel around for a light switch
我好像找到了一个
I think I found one
好大一盏台灯
That's a big lamp
还是很黑
It's still pretty dark
别的也打开吧
Let's turn on these other ones
等下  也许不应该
Wait, maybe we shouldn't--
行了
There
现在我不怎么怕了
I'm much less scared now
你们激怒了海之霸的幽灵
You have angered the spirits of the Chum Bucket
现在你们的灵魂
And now your souls
就要归我了
will be mine
看招  你个吸血鬼德古拉
Take this, you Dracula
是痞老板
It's Plankton
怎么回事
What's happening?
那些失灵的机器
Those malfunctioning machines
打开了某种幽灵通道
are opening up some kind of spectral gateway
幽灵
Ghosts
他们为什么会打扮成牛仔的样子
Why are they dressed like cowboys?
海之霸可是我低价买来的
Well, I bought the Chum Bucket cheap
因为它一开始建在古代牛仔墓地上边
because it was built
on an ancient cowboy burial ground
而这墓地又建在宠物公墓上边
Which was built on top of a pet cemetery
再加上沉船
And a shipwreck
再加上史前焦油坑
And a prehistoric tar pit
我还能怎么说
What can I say?
我就爱贪便宜
I love a good deal
红辣椒粉
Paprika
肉豆蔻
Nutmeg
天啊  痞老板
Boy, Plankton
你过万圣节简直是拼了
you sure go all out for Halloween
至少我们在外面挺安全的  对吧
At least we're safe out here, right?
错了
Wrong
未完待续
不给糖就捣蛋
Trick or treat
蛋好意思
Egg-scuse us
好耶  宝贝
Yeah, baby
那些烦人鬼滚出我餐厅了
Those pesky poltergeists are out of my restaurant
我要回去睡觉了
Welp, I'm going back to bed
痞老板
Plankton
不能让比奇堡一直这么闹鬼了
We can't let Bikini Bottom stay haunted
为什么
Why not?
今天可是万圣节
It's Halloween
大家都爱死了
They love it
你听
Listen
我才不爱
I do not love this
好吧
Fine
我知道可以用什么说服你来帮忙
I know what'll convince you to help
一首歌
A song
来
Well--
好了好了
Alright, fine
只要你不唱歌  我就去把幽灵抓回来
I'll get the ghosts back as long as you don't sing
万圣节本来就够恐怖了
Halloween is scary enough
好了
There
一个工业级幽灵吸尘器
One industrial ghost vacuum
听候差遣
at your service
现在就需要个东西来收纳那群幽灵
All we need now is something to contain those ghosts
要方方黄黄伸缩自如的东西
Something absorbent yet porous
你确定这样安全吗
And you're sure this is safe?
大概不安全
Probably not
甚至可能会要你命
It might even kill you
我要按按钮
I wanna push the button
停
现在就只要摧毁他的身体
Now all we have to do is destroy his body
这闹鬼问题就能彻底解决了
and this ghost problem will be solved for good
安静
Silence
我们诸多亡魂已经愤怒了上千年
We spirits have been angry for millennia
知道为什么吗
And do you know why?
因为今天是万圣节
Because it's Halloween
你们从来没要过糖吗
and you've never been trick-or-treating?
还真是
Actually, yes
那可是我们
It's our
未了的夙愿
unfinished business
所以说只要带他们去要糖
So we just have to take them all trick-or-treating
他们就会离开吗
and they'll go away?
你们说怎么样呢  幽灵们
Well, what do you say, ghosts?
我觉得不错
Sounds good to me
好啊  兄弟
Aye-aye, matey
那就让这些幽灵
Then let's give these ghosts
过上他们来世最美好的万圣节吧
the best Halloween of their afterlives
肯尼阿猫
你好
Hello?
不给糖就捣蛋
Trick or treat
奶油硬糖
Butterscotch
好吃
Yum
万岁
Hooray
谢谢大家
Thank you, everyone
你们让这次万圣节好玩到要我们命
You have made this a Halloween to die for
第二次
again
我们终于可以安息了
Now we can finally be at peace
再次感谢  搭档们
Thanks again, partners
谢了
Thanks
真是的
Aww, man
这下得重新要一遍糖了
Now we have to trick-or-treat all over again
等等我
Wait for me
别让我多花一分钟
Don't make me spend another minute
陪着这些白痴
with these idiots
果不其然
Typical
快去捡
编剧/导演
翻译: 1440kHz
CG动画制作公司
美术总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
水母田
好耶
Oh, yeah
加油  小蜗
Come on, Gary
就是这样
That's it, boy
快捡回来
Bring it on home
小蜗小蜗
G-A-R-Y
不需要靠空气活
He don't need no air supply
小蜗
Gary
四十五分钟
Forty-five minutes
破你最快时间记录了
Your fastest time yet
这球我们拥有了一辈子
We've had this ball forever
我依然记得自己最初把球给你的时候
Why, I still remember when I first gave it to you
小蜗
Gary
我有个惊喜
I have a surprise
是颗球
It's a ball
小蜗  这次投球我要加把劲
Alright, Gary, I'm gonna put a little pepper on this pitch
我做到了  老妈
I did it, Mommy
我踢到球了
I kicked the ball
不要
No
小蜗的球
Gary's ball
一个字都不用再说  小蜗
Don't say another word, Gary
我知道你在想什么
I know just what you're thinking
我们要跳进那个海沟
We are gonna jump down into that trench
捡回你的友谊之球
and get your friendship ball back
至死方休
or we're gonna die trying
我们要死了
We're gonna die
还好有这一大堆遗失的球垫着做缓冲
Good thing this huge pile of lost balls broke our fall
怎么在这么大一堆球里找到我们的球
How are we gonna find our ball in this giant pile?
原来它就掉在
It was just sitting here
这堆被咬过的可怕骨头堆上
on this gruesome mound of gnawed bones
抱歉  我们不是故意要碰你骨头的
Sorry, we didn't mean to touch your bones
只是在找我们那颗特别的友谊之球
We were just looking for our special friendship ball
你看
See?
既然友谊之球找回来了
Now that we've got our friendship ball back
我绝对不会再放开它
I'm never letting it go again
我说过  我绝对不会再放开这颗
Like I said, I'm never letting go of this
球
ball
还不算太糟嘛
Yeah, this isn't so bad
跑远点去接  小蜗
Go long, Gary
你马上就能得救了  小蜗
You're as good as rescued, Gary
找到你了
Gotcha
好耶
Yeah
它长得好像章鱼哥
That looks like Squidward
我们的球
Our ball
成功了  小蜗
We did it, Gary
我们简直天下无
We are truly invincib--
小  小蜗
G-Gary
我要
I'm gonna
丢给你
Throw you
这颗球
The ball
快啊  小蜗
Hurry, Gary
我没法拖住它多久了
I can't hold her back much longer
自己
Save
保重
Yourself
小蜗  为什么要放弃你的球呢
Gary, why did you give up your ball?
你说这球只是个玩具是什么意思
What do you mean the ball was just a toy?
我们创造的回忆才重要  球并不重要
It's the memories we made that matter, not the ball?
我们可以玩这颗新球来创造新的回忆
And we can make new memories with this new ball?
小蜗  你好聪明
Gary, you are so wise
过来吧
Get over here
我做到了  老妈
I did it, Mommy
我又踢到球了
I kicked the ball again